There is a rumor going around
that a YouTuber in this space just made
$11.5 million launching a new product.
And I've got on the grapevine some of the
stats surrounding it.
And whatever level you're at,
just starting an online business,
you've been doing
it 5 years, or even a 20-year veteran,
this is going to shock you, but also make
you feel better at the same time.
11.5 million, and that's USD.
So it turns out that the ticket price for
this offer was $1,500.
Now, $1,500 can seem like quite a lot,
but there are two real modes that you have
in business. You have B2C,
business to consumer, which
is pretty much business on
hard mode. So those of you
that have got coaching clients,
you're having to get
people's post-tax income, which means
that if someone's going to pay you 80
pounds
for something,
they have to earn about 120 or 130,
then pay tax on the money,
then have that 80 pounds. Whereas
when you do B2B, business to business,
people can
use pre-tax income,
so they can pay from the business.
So 80 pounds earned can just be spent 80
pounds.
So when you're doing a B2C business,
you must take in mind
that everything's always
going to be a little bit harder because
people are paying with their own cash.
When you're in business to business,
they can write off the cost.
So people that do my mentorship,
link in the description,
they'll get an invoice
from that, give it to their accountant,
and that'll be taken off their
profitability. The business will pay.
Doesn't mean it's free,
but it means it's about 30%
or 40% cheaper than paying with
your own money.
So $1,500 for a business-to-business
product isn't
crazy. My mentorship's twice that. Now,
here's the crazy part.
What we do is we put brackets.
The conversion rate for the sale was
1.5%. Now, everyone can think that 1.5%
is a really bad conversion rate.
Some people build out a landing page,
which is a website
that you host for people
to make a decision to buy stuff.
Some people are like, "Eh, coaching calls,
eh, DM
people." Think about it.
When I buy an Eight Sleep, which is a
temperature-controlled mattress, which
is one of the best things you could ever
spend your money on,
I'm spending five grand on a mattress
cover.
I go to the website,
I get all the information about it,
all the benefits.
I can see the reviews,
and I make a decision there.
Someone comes to the website
and doesn't want a mattress. Boo-hoo.
When I'm buying something from Apple,
very rarely do I need to go in
and speak to a
sales consultant.
I already know what I want.
And actually,
I would much rather configure my MacBook
and use AI
and chat away to find out the specs than
actually speak to someone.
Today,
I'm buying a new washer-dryer combo for my
house.
I've already decided which one.
I don't need a person to make a decision
to buy.
Not to mention, if this person
was to use a sales team that get 10%
commission,
he would've lost $1.5 million from the
launch, when
quite clearly, he didn't need it. Okay,
gets crazier.
So you're probably thinking,
for a 1.5% conversion rate on a $1,500
product, how big was the email list?
It was 511,000.
Now, 511,000 seems like a huge amount,
which it is.
But I've got email lists over 400K,
and I ain't got $11.5 million.
So 500,000 can seem like a million miles
away because your following might not even
be 10% of that. But this
is where the kind of genius part comes in.
The YouTuber in question has 6 million
subs.
So when we look down at the launch,
it completely makes sense.
I'm going to talk you through it.
So this isn't even 10% of his total
audience. I've got a rule
that you should always aspire for 20% of
your following
to be on your email list. So
if you're not there yet,
you should probably take a
bit of time away from trying to grow your
audience, and instead try and get their
contact details or their email address
from them.
Because the content
that you put out to grow your audience
is a little bit
different to the content you put out to
get their contact information.
And it's almost like being a farmer.
You could look at your field and go, "Hmm,
do we need to plant seeds, or do we need
to harvest crops?" And
if you have the same mentality in your
business, you can
appreciate what you need to do at this
period of time.
Do you need to harvest data from your
audience,
or do you need to focus on growing
it? If you're near that 20% mark,
grow the audience.
If you're not, harvest the data.
Because although it's exciting to grow
your
audience and have a post go viral
and get new customers,
another thing you've got
to consider is if you double your email
database,
you're going to double the amount
of people that are going to your website.
Whenever people double their email list,
they often double their income, and I'll
show you why. This conversion rate
is often fixed.
And sure,
we could do some A/B split testing.
We could change the title
or the colors on the page,
and we could have an A
version,
and then a B version might have a 1.4
conversion rate.
And we go, "Okay,
cool." Then we might have a C version
that has a 1.6 conversion
rate. Cool. But it's very rare
that you're going to have a discrepancy
between this
where one's 1.5%, one's 10%,
and one's 22%.
Because the intent of the amount of
nurturing that's going to have happened
with
them watching the content,
the amount of people
and type of people that come to the
email list,
they're already pretty nurtured by this
point.
So chances are that just 98% of people
just can't really afford
it,
or they're not ready to buy at this period
of time.
And a lot of gurus will force you to focus
on this.
And I do think that improving your font
size and getting a good,
well-curated and designed landing page
is fantastic for these.
But for a lot of you,
increasing your email list
is such an easy task that you can
do. So for any of you that are under
that 20%,
the next pieces of content you put
out should be with getting people's email
addresses in mind.
And by the way,
I help thousands of businesses with this
every year.
If you're interested in my mentorship,
I've got to put a link in the description.
And if you want to get access to all the
information but not pay the
fortune to get access to me
and my coaches, there
is a business blueprint you can
look into as well,
which goes through this in more detail.
So for any of you out there,
irrespective of where you are, even
if you've only got
about 10% of your audience on your email
list, you should actually be celebrating
because that's pretty good. And even
if you're only hitting a 1.5% or 1.4%
conversion rate, that's great.
Because let's do this maths for another
business.
So we'll get rid of this for a sec.
Let's say you've got 7,000 followers.
And if you're not there yet,
it's not hard to get to.
If you are there yet, whatever.
You also only have 10% of your audience
on your email list.
So that's going to be 700.
Of which,
let's say a 1.5% conversion rate.
That's going to equate to 10.5 buyers.
Now,
if you're someone that's charging $75 a
week for coaching, that's
$750 a week, which
is 3,000 a month in monthly
recurring revenue. And although
that isn't enough to get a Lamborghini,
let's just
look again. 7,000 followers,
which isn't very difficult for most of you
to get to
in maybe 6 to 12 months of posting.
10% on your email list
is half of what I told
you that you needed. So again,
just on the simple maths,
if you're able to get that
to 20%, which I wanted,
and we keep the conversion the same,
that takes you to
$6,000 a month in monthly recurring
revenue.
Then if you manage to hire someone with
the money that you've made, and you take
your conversion rate to 3% through six
months of A/B split
testing,
maybe using a certain professional
platform, getting a professional VSL.
Again,
you've just doubled your conversion rate.
You're now at $12,000 a month monthly
recurring revenue from 7,000 in your
audience. And then every time you grow,
you just keep the same amount of
equations on the way down.
And I don't care who you are,
you can live off this, and
you can do really well. Now,
the beautiful thing
is whether you're at 3K, whether
you're at 6K, whether you're at 12K,
that is enough to quit your job and go all
in on creating social media content,
which only sends this up.
10K, 20K, 50K. The beginning of that
is the hardest part
because let's be real,
when I started on social media, I
was a very good personal
trainer. Do you want to know why I
was a very good personal trainer?
Because I just spent the last five years
just personal training.
Now I'm a very good content creator.
Do you know why?
Because I spent the last five years just
creating content.
You, where you are right now,
are an accumulation of everything you've
done in the
last three years So if you're not
that great at running a business
or pumping out
content right now, for a lot of you,
I don't blame you because you should have
been
busy the last three years being a good
coach.
With the link in the description,
Short-Form Content Mastery,
I teach you how to
make better content so you can get to
that point that I showed you on the board,
that you can quit your job
and you can go all in.
Then you can become a full-time content
creator that feeds that funnel.
And I'm not trying to say there's any
crazy maths here.
I've gone so pessimistic on each one.
Only 7,000 followers,
only 10% on the email list, only 1.5%
conversion rate, and that's a life
that you could rent an apartment,
get a good
MacBook, get a good camera,
have a good gym membership,
have a membership at a
local sauna or ice bath,
and still go out with your partner for two
meals a week.
This is the world we're going into.
Now, these 7,000 people, they
are not following you, they are following
your brand.
And I had to get my mate to understand
this the other day.
I said to him,
"People don't care about your business.
They care about your brand.
They care about your values.
They care about what you stand for,
and they care
about what you do on a daily basis to help
people." But like me today, the reason
I'm here is to help you guys
and to make money from you.
Don't get me wrong.
If you think about it,
I'm giving you industry secrets
that take you from morons to
competitors. I know morons is horrible,
but let's be honest, some of you are out
there still taking pictures of your lunch
and topless selfies or whatever.
For me, the more of you
that understand this stuff,
the more of you I've got to
compete with because you get very good at
content very quick.
So that's why I charge you money. AI
is going to replace a lot of jobs in the
next
few years. Data analysts, accountants.
You guys know that.
I don't need to tell you that.
But it's going to be a very long time,
years, before
they take over personal brand.
So in the next three years, if there
was any skill
that you want to get really good at,
it should be making content for all the
reasons I've just shown you.
Short-Form Content Mastery, $99,
link in the
description. PT Starter Kit,
I'm not actually sure how much that is.
Link in the description.
Business Blueprint,
access to all the lessons that you can
implement. Business Mentorship,
all the lessons, plus access to me
and my coaches.
And YouTube Silver Play Button,
currently only 199 for those of you
that want to do
well on YouTube. Get into those.
You don't need crazy conversions and crazy
followings like the person
that made $11 million.
But what you can do
is look at what they've done
and realize this is not as
difficult as you may think it
was going to be.
And just think, the next three years,
at the end of it,
you're either a weapon that
can churn out content
or you're in the exact same place
that you are now.
There's no in between.
So exit this video wisely. Bye-bye.